<idea-plugin>
    <id>dev.ckob.lazygit</id>
    <name>Lazygit</name>
    <vendor url="https://ckob.dev">ckob</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
    <p>Bring the speed and elegance of <b>Lazygit</b> directly into your JetBrains IDE. No more context switching between your terminal and your editor.</p>

    <h3>✨ Zero-Config Native File Editing</h3>
    <p>Forget about writing custom bash scripts or fighting with complex <code>$EDITOR</code> configurations. This plugin features a custom, high-performance IPC (Inter-Process Communication) bridge. <b>Simply press <code>e</code> on any file in Lazygit</b>, and it will instantly open right in your IDE's editor. It works completely out of the box in <i>any</i> IntelliJ-based IDE without a single line of extra configuration.</p>

    <h3>🚀 Key Features</h3>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Immersive UI:</b> Toggles Lazygit in a dedicated, full-screen editor tab rather than a cramped tool window, giving your git graph the space it deserves.</li>
        <li><b>Instant Edit:</b> Native file opening via IPC. Hit <code>e</code> and start typing.</li>
        <li><b>Smart Lifecycle:</b> Automatically cleans up and closes the IDE tab the moment you exit Lazygit (pressing <code>q</code>).</li>
        <li><b>IdeaVim Friendly:</b> Easily map the toggle action (<code>:action Lazygit.Toggle</code>) to your favorite Vim keybinding for a seamless workflow.</li>
    </ul>

    <br/>
    <p><i>Note: You must have the <a href="https://github.com/jesseduffield/lazygit">Lazygit executable</a> installed on your system to use this plugin.</i></p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
    Version (0.1.2):
    <ul>
        <li>Feature: Added support for opening multiple selected files at once (using visual/select mode and pressing 'e').</li>
    </ul>
    <br/>
    Version (0.1.1):
    <ul>
        <li>Fix: Correctly isolate lazygit instances per project window to fix file opening in multiple IDE instances.</li>
    </ul>
    <br/>
    Initial release (0.1.0):
    <ul>
        <li>Toggle LazyGit in a full-screen editor tab.</li>
        <li>Native file opening (press 'e' in LazyGit to open in IDE).</li>
        <li>Automatic closing of editor tab when exiting LazyGit.</li>
        <li>IdeaVim support via :action Lazygit.Toggle.</li>
    </ul>
    ]]>
    </change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.plugins.terminal</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <fileEditorProvider implementation="dev.ckob.lazygit.LazygitEditorProvider"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="Lazygit.Toggle" class="dev.ckob.lazygit.LazygitAction" text="Lazygit: Toggle" description="Toggle LazyGit window">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="ctrl alt g"/> </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>